William N. Fenton Papers 1933-2000 Mss.Ms.Coll.20
American Philosophical Society
- Series VI. Photographs, 1880-1993; 12 boxes; 7 linear feet
  - False Faces of the Iroquois (Box Series VI-2)
    - Folder #11, [1987] (Box Series VI-4)
      captions
    - Folder #12, [1987?] (Box Series VI-4)
      Figures
      -See oversized
    - Folder #13, 198- (Box Series VI-4)
    - Folder #14, n.d. (Box Series VI-4)
      Orig. encl. in Ser.III, F.F. of the Iroquois--Notes #2 (1930s-1940s, 1980s)
    - Folder #15, [1955] (Box Series VI-4)
      Orig. encl. in Ser.III, F.F. of the Iroquois--Notes #5 (1930s-1940s, 1980s)
    - Folder #16, 1940 (Box Series VI-4)
      Orig. encl. in Ser.III, F.F. of the Iroquois--Notes #6 (1930s-1940s, 1980s)
  - Fenton, John William and Jones Snow, [1933] (Box Series VI-4)
    Neg. #129
  - Fenton, William N. and Henry Redeye, [1942 or 1943] (Box Series VI-4)
  - Fenton, William N. with Adolph Schultz and Mrs. Daryll Forde, [1956] (Box Series VI-4)
  - Fenton, William N.--I.D. card, 1958 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Fenton, William N., [1962] (Box Series VI-4)
  - Fenton, William N., 1964 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Kidder, Alfred V. II ? (Box Series VI-4)
  - Lips, Eva ? (Box Series VI-4)
  - Fire Football, [Sep.? 1937] (Box Series VI-4)
  - "Fish Drives Among the Cornplanter Senecas", n.d. (Box Series VI-4)
  - "Fleetfoot", [1970] (Box Series VI-4)
  - Fogelson, Raymond David (Box Series VI-4)
  - "The Cherokee Ball Game: A Study in Southeastern Ethnology", n.d. (Box Series VI-4)
  - Food Utensils, 1933 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Jacobs, John (Box Series VI-4)
  - "From Longhouse to Ranch-Type House: The Second Housing Revolution of the Seneca Indians", 1934, 1965, n.d. (Box Series VI-4)
    - Seneca dance spectators, 1934
  - General, Chief and Mrs. Alex, [1956] (Box Series VI-4)
  - Gibson, Simeon, 1907 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Green Corn Dance, 1933-1934 (Box Series VI-4)
    - Old Seneca, 1933-1934
  - Ground, Benjamin, 1935 (Box Series VI-4)
    - Benjamin Ground, 1935
  - Ground, H. (Box Series VI-4)
    - Folder #1, [1935] (Box Series VI-4)
      Neg. #293
    - Folder #2, [1935] (Box Series VI-4)
      Neg. #294
  - Hale Tombstone in Clinton, Ontario, Jun. 1962 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Harris, Helen and Charles, 19 May 1990 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Hayes, John Craddock (Box Series VI-4)
    - Folder #1, [12 Aug. 1965] (Box Series VI-4)
    - Folder #2, 25 Jun. 1966 (Box Series VI-4)
    - Folder #3, 1986 (Box Series VI-4)
  - Herbarium: Allegany Seneca Systematics, n.d. (Box Series VI-5)
  - Indian Family (Box Series VI-5)
  - Indians Shucking Corn (Box Series VI-5)
  - International Congress of Americanists (31st: Sao Paulo, Brazil), 1954 (Box Series VI-5)
  - International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences (4th: Vienna), 1952 (Box Series VI-5)
  - International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences (5th: Philadelphia), 1956; 3 folders (Box Series VI-5)
  - International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences (7th: Moscow), 1964 (Box Series VI-5)
  - International Union of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences, 1963 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Iroquois Medicines, n.d. (Box Series VI-5)
  - Iroquois Objects, n.d. (Box Series VI-5)
  - Iroquois moccasins, pouch, and bag, 1936-1937
    - Iroquois moccasins, 1936-1937
    - Iroquois pouch, 1936-1937
  - Jacobs, John (Box Series VI-5)
    -See Ser.VI, Food Utensils
  - Jimerson, Alice Lee, n.d. (Box Series VI-5)
  - Jones, Albert and Avery Jimerson, [Jun.? 1956] (Box Series VI-5)
  - Kadenbach, Peter, [1980] (Box Series VI-5)
  - Kidder, Alfred V. II (Box Series VI-5)
    -See Ser.VI, Fenton, William N.
  - Kinzua Dam, n.d. (Box Series VI-5)
  - Kinzua Dam--Negatives, Jul. 1963 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Seneca, Cornelius (and wife) (Box Series VI-5)
  - Lacrosse Field, 1953 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Leach, MacEdward, 1959 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Leacock, Eleanor Burke, n.d. (Box Series VI-5)
  - Lips, Eva (Box Series VI-5)
  - [Longhouse], n.d. (Box Series VI-5)
  - Longhouse (Oklahoma Seneca-Cayuga), Aug. 1969 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Mansion House, Kenwood, N.Y., [1948] (Box Series VI-5)
  - Mask (Cranbrook Institute of Science), 1989 (Box Series VI-5)
  - "Maskette", [1971] (Box Series VI-5)
  - Materia Medica and Seneca Place Names (Box Series VI-5)
  - Mid-Winter Festival, 1935-1941 (Box Series VI-5)
    - Big heads: masked heralds, 1935-1941
  - Montour, Josiah (Box Series VI-5)
    -See Ser.VI, Speck, Frank G.
  - Museum of the American Indian (Box Series VI-5)
    Negs. #463, 495, 842, 905a, 905d, 905h, 920
  - Museum of the American Indian. Fenton Collection, 1931 (Box Series VI-5)
  - National Museum of Canada (Iroquois exhibit), Nov. 1962 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Onondaga Longhouse Food Spirit Festival, 1952 (Box Series VI-5)
  - Parker on the Iroquois, 1945, n.d. (Box Series VI-5)
  - Pipe, [1971] (Box Series VI-5)
  - Pipe (Catlinite), [1971] (Box Series VI-5)
  - Pipe (Stone), n.d. (Box Series VI-5)
  - Redeye, Henry, 15 Sep. 1933 (Box Series VI-6)
    Neg. #148
    -See also Ser.VI, Fenton, William N. and Henry Redeye
  - Roseberry, Tip, 1955 (Box Series VI-6)
  - Roy, Edouard, [1939] (Box Series VI-6)
  - Ryan, Allan J., 1984, 1986-1987, n.d. (Box Series VI-6)
  - Seneca, Cornelius--Negatives (Box Series VI-6)
    -See Ser.VI, Kinzua Dam--Negatives
  - Seneca Indians at Coldspring on the Allegheny Reservation. Journal of Field Expedition to the, Jun.-Sep. 1933 (Box Series VI-6)
    - Coldspring Lacrosse team, 1933
    - Ella T. Jimmerson, 1933
    - Jones Snow (Hawk), 1933
    - Lacrosse at Coldspring, 1933
    - Seneca dwelling, 1933
    - William N. Fenton, 1933
  - "The Seneca Society of Faces", 1935-1940, 1962 (Box Series VI-6)
  - "Six Nations Indian Chiefs of the Iroquois Confederacy", 1910 (Box Series VI-6)
  - Sky, Howard, 1956, n.d. (Box Series VI-6)
  - Sky, Howard, n.d. (Box Series VI-6)
  - Snow, Jones (Box Series VI-6)
    -See Ser.VI, Fenton, John William and Jones Snow, [1933]
  - Social and Ceremonial Organization on the Six Nations Reserve in 1910 (Box Series VI-6)
  - Speck, Frank G. and Josiah Montour, 3 Nov. 1945 (Box Series VI-6)
    Neg. Vol. XII, 13
  - "Wah-nee-nah. Mohawk Indian Maid, Vocalist" (Box Series VI-6)
  - Wampum (Ethnohistory), n.d. (Box Series VI-6)
  - Wampum (Horatio Hale), 1880 (Box Series VI-6)
  - Wampum. Museum of the American Indian (Box Series VI-6)
  - Wampum. New York State Museum, n.d. (Box Series VI-6)
  - Wampum (Newberry Library), [1979] (Box Series VI-6)
  - Wampum belt (Huron), 27 Sep. 1967 (Box Series VI-6)
  - Wampum belts (Roddy, Thomas W.), n.d. (Box Series VI-6)
    - Wampum belts
  - Wampum transfer. Museum of the American Indian (Box Series VI-6)
    - Folder #1, May 8, 1988 (Box Series VI-6)
      - Wampum transfer, 1988
      - Wampum
    - Folder #2, May 8, 1988 (Box Series VI-6)
    - Folder #3--Negatives, May 8, 1988 (Box Series VI-6)
  - Wampum treaty belt (General Anthony Wayne), [1970] (Box Series VI-6)
  - Warrior's path, Aug. 1938 (Box Series VI-6)
  - [Wooden vase?], 1941 (Box Series VI-6)
  - Negatives no. 4-347 (Box Series VI-7)
  - Negatives no. 348-636 (Box Series VI-8)
  - Negatives no. 637-868c (Box Series VI-9)
  - Negatives no. 868d-933, vol. XI-vol. XII #83 (Box Series VI-10)
  - Empty negative album (Box Series VI-11)
  - Empty negative album (Box Series VI-12)
- Series VII. Recordings
  - Fenton Children, circa 1950s; Mss.Ms.Coll.20.Recordings.1; 1.0 Reel(s) 1 sound tape reel
  - International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences (7th, 1964: Moscow), Mss.Ms.Coll.20.Recordings.2; 3.0 Item(s) 3 SoundScriber phonograph discs
  - Rensselaersville Memorial Session, October 4, 1996; Mss.Ms.Coll.20.Recordings.3; 1.0 Tape(s) 1 audiocassette
- Series I-VI. Oversized (Oversize 1)
  - Folder 1 (Oversize 1)
    Contains oversized materials from Series I, Correspondence.
    - Allen, Hope, 26 August 1948 (Oversize 1, Folder 1)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1986 (Oversize 1, Folder 1)
    - Fadden, Ray, 1966, n.d. (Oversize 1, Folder 1)
    - Mallery, A. H., 10 August 1941 - 12 June 1942 (Oversize 1, Folder 1)
    - Museum of the American Indian, 14 April 1981 (Oversize 1, Folder 1)
    - Sky, Howard (Oversize 1, Folder 1)
  - Folder 2 (Oversize 1)
    Contains oversized materials from Series IIa, Subject Files.
    - Akwesasne Mohawk Counselor Organization, n.d. (Oversize 1, Folder 2)
    - Cornplanter, Jesse J., 1936 (Oversize 1, Folder 2)
    - Kinzua Dam, 10 April 1957 (Oversize 1, Folder 2)
    - Kinzua Dam -- Clippings, 16 September 1966 - 17 September 1966 (Oversize 1, Folder 2)
  - Folder 3 (Oversize 1)
    - Musuem of the American Indian, Heye Foundation -- Clippings, 8 April 1986 - [1987] (Oversize 1, Folder 3)
    - Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation -- Comprehensive Plan, 1986 (Oversize 1, Folder 3)
    - Thomas Indian School, 1846 (Oversize 1, Folder 3)
  - Folder 4 (Oversize 1)
    Contains oversized materials from Series IIb, Iroquois Documentary History Project.
    - Condolence, 1725, 1730 (Oversize 1, Folder 4)
    - Covenant Chain, 31 July 1684 - 6 August 1684 (Oversize 1, Folder 4)
    - Deeds, 1683, 1685 (Oversize 1, Folder 4)
    - Treaties, 1687-1745 (Oversize 1, Folder 4)
    - "The Treaty Held with the Indians of the Six Nations at Philadelphia, July, 1742" -- From The American Magazine, October 1743 (Oversize 1, Folder 4)
  - Folder 5 (Oversize 1)
    Contains oversized materials from Series III - Series VI.
    - Customs of the American Indians Compared with the Customs of Primitive Times by Father Joseph Francois Lafitau -- Notes and Research, Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005 (Oversize 1, Folder 5)
      From Series III, Works by Fenton.
    - "Factionalism in American Indian Society" -- Manuscript, 1952; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005 (Oversize 1, Folder 5)
    - "Tonawanda Senecas Entertain Six Nations Meeting Delegates" -- Page Proof, [1936?]; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005 (Oversize 1, Folder 5)
    - "The Medical History of the Columbus Voyages" -- Manuscript, 26 October 1954; Davis, David J. (Oversize 1, Folder 5)
      From Series IV, Works by Others.
    - "Passenger Pigeon Hunts among Cornplanter Seneca", 1942 (Oversize 1, Folder 5)
      From Series V, Research Notes.
    - The False Faces of the Iroquois, [1987?] (Oversize 1, Folder 5)
      From Series VI, Photographs. Figures.
    - Map -- Allegany Indian Reservation, 1955 (Oversize 1, Folder 5)
      From Series VI, Photographs.
    - Map -- Western Pennsylvania and New York by John Adlum, [ca. 1791] (Oversize 1, Folder 5)